<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.5">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-01-03T02:57:42-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">MMDG</title><subtitle>Sitio oficial del Museo Municipal de Guayaquil</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Los Constante, cuatro generaciones de artistas</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/los-constante/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Los Constante, cuatro generaciones de artistas" /><published>2020-01-02T01:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-01-02T01:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/los-constante</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/los-constante/">&lt;p&gt;Primera Exposición del 2020 que se realiza en el Museo Municipal de Guayaquil, se expondrá el legado de una familia dedicada al arte por varias generaciones. Y es que el  arte, en la vida de los Constante, más allá de ser un hábito que tienen en común, representa una manera de vivir, de encontrarse en el mundo y expresarse ante él.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;Esta cualidad representativa de la familia ha recorrido generación tras generación, y ha permitido que cada uno de ellos, la plasme de una manera diferente. La exposición “Los Constante” exhibe obras de los miembros de la familia que han optado por este medio de manifestación para expresar sus sentimientos con las características propias década uno, pero teniendo en común más que el apellido, el arte en sus venas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Teobaldo Constante&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artista ecuatoriano, destacado caricaturista para diarios y revistas nacionales. Sin embargo, su obra se extiende a oleos, carboncillos, acuarelas, y pasteles. A menudo se podía destacar la sátira entre sus ilustraciones, pero adicionalmente se lo veía incursionando con retratos y desnudos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theo Constante&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artista ecuatoriano, considerado entre los grandes maestros de la pintura nacional, siendo acreedor del premio Eugenio Espejo por su brillante trayectoria y legado en la pintura latinoamericana. Su obra incluye óleos, acrílicos, esculturas y murales. Las mismas que fueron llevadas, representando al país, con gran acogida en Europa como en Estados Unidos.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hellen Constante&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artista ecuatoriana de destacada trayectoria, ha sido ganadora de un número de concursos a nivel nacional entre ellos el Salón de Julio. Sumado a eso ha tenido una carrera de más de 35 años, en las que ha tenido gran éxito en exhibiciones tanto locales como en el extranjero. Recientemente ha llevado su obra a Asia y Europa donde ha sido recibida de gran manera. La obra de la artista se extiende desde cuadros de óleo, a esculturas y murales que pueden ser vistas por la ciudad de Guayaquil.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Theo Marmolejo Constante&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artista ecuatoriano, quien con gran éxito ha llevado su obra tanto a Asia como a Estados Unidos, destacándose en exhibición personales como grupales. A nivel local ha participado en salones de pintura y concursos de gran manera. En su obra sobresale la mezcla de colores para expresar naturaleza humana y su perspectiva a ella.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Alejandro  Marmolejo Constante&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artista  ecuatoriano,  quien con grandes participaciones a    nivel    local    y    en    el extranjero  ha  desarrollado una destacada carrera como artista.  Su  obra  de  origen ilustrativo  se  inspira  en  la naturaleza   propia    de    la costa ecuatoriana para estampar imágenes de paisajes  autóctonos  de   la localidad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Luis Marmolejo  Constante&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Artista ecuatoriano, quien ha participado  activamente  en concursos  y   exhibiciones  a nivel nacional e internacional. Recientemente ha destacado en  concursos municipales en la   ciudad   de   Guayaquil   al participar  y  ser  ganador  en dos ocasiones de los mismos. Su obra  está  inspirada  en  la naturaleza     vegetal     y la mezcla    abstracta    de     los colores   que   conforman   la misma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Esta muestra será inaugurada el jueves 9 de enero a las 18h30 y concluirá el 31 de enero del 2020. El horario de atención al público es de martes a sábados de 09h00 a 17h30.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>fernando</name></author><summary type="html">Primera Exposición del 2020 que se realiza en el Museo Municipal de Guayaquil, se expondrá el legado de una familia dedicada al arte por varias generaciones. Y es que el arte, en la vida de los Constante, más allá de ser un hábito que tienen en común, representa una manera de vivir, de encontrarse en el mundo y expresarse ante él.Esta cualidad representativa de la familia ha recorrido generación tras generación, y ha permitido que cada uno de ellos, la plasme de una manera diferente. La exposición “Los Constante” exhibe obras de los miembros de la familia que han optado por este medio de manifestación para expresar sus sentimientos con las características propias década uno, pero teniendo en común más que el apellido, el arte en sus venas.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="https://res.cloudinary.com/magnvs/image/upload/v1577970252/ymzqgrphlpa59hc57l7r.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Could we reinvent the charm of old cities</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/charm-old-cities/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Could we reinvent the charm of old cities" /><published>2020-01-01T20:30:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-01-01T20:30:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/charm-old-cities</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/charm-old-cities/">&lt;p&gt;Bucharest’s history alternated periods of development and decline from the early settlements in antiquity until its consolidation as the national capital of Romania late in the 19th century. First mentioned as the “Citadel of București” in 1459, it became the residence of the famous Wallachian prince Vlad III the Impaler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;early-18th-century-woodcut-of-bucharest&quot;&gt;Early 18th century woodcut of Bucharest&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ottomans appointed Greek administrators (Phanariotes) to run the town from the 18th century. A short-lived revolt initiated by Tudor Vladimirescu in 1821 led to the end of the rule of Constantinople Greeks in Bucharest.[19]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Old Princely Court (Curtea Veche) was erected by Mircea Ciobanul in the mid-16th century. Under subsequent rulers, Bucharest was established as the summer residence of the royal court. During the years to come, it competed with Târgoviște on the status of capital city after an increase in the importance of southern Muntenia brought about by the demands of the suzerain power – the Ottoman Empire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bucharest finally became the permanent location of the Wallachian court after 1698 (starting with the reign of Constantin Brâncoveanu).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Partly destroyed by natural disasters and rebuilt several times during the following 200 years, and hit by Caragea’s plague in 1813–14, the city was wrested from Ottoman control and occupied at several intervals by the Habsburg Monarchy (1716, 1737, 1789) and Imperial Russia (three times between 1768 and 1806). It was placed under Russian administration between 1828 and the Crimean War, with an interlude during the Bucharest-centred 1848 Wallachian revolution. Later, an Austrian garrison took possession after the Russian departure (remaining in the city until March 1857). On 23 March 1847, a fire consumed about 2,000 buildings, destroying a third of the city.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><summary type="html">Bucharest’s history alternated periods of development and decline from the early settlements in antiquity until its consolidation as the national capital of Romania late in the 19th century. First mentioned as the “Citadel of București” in 1459, it became the residence of the famous Wallachian prince Vlad III the Impaler.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/home.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Welcome to Jekyll!</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-jekyll/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Welcome to Jekyll!" /><published>2020-01-01T20:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-01-01T20:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/welcome-to-jekyll/">&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;https://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>fernando</name></author><summary type="html">You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/demo1.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Markdown Example</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/markup-example/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Markdown Example" /><published>2020-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/markup-example</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/markup-example/">&lt;p&gt;You’ll find this post in your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;jekyll serve&lt;/code&gt;, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated. Something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To add new posts, simply add a file in the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;_posts&lt;/code&gt; directory that follows the convention &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;YYYY-MM-DD-name-of-post.ext&lt;/code&gt; and includes the necessary front matter. Take a look at the source for this post to get an idea about how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Jekyll also offers powerful support for code snippets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-ruby&quot; data-lang=&quot;ruby&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;def&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;puts&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;Hi, &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;#{&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;name&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;si&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;end&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;print_hi&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s1&quot;&gt;'Tom'&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;#=&amp;gt; prints 'Hi, Tom' to STDOUT.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com/docs/home&quot;&gt;Jekyll docs&lt;/a&gt; for more info on how to get the most out of Jekyll. File all bugs/feature requests at &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jekyll/jekyll&quot;&gt;Jekyll’s GitHub repo&lt;/a&gt;. If you have questions, you can ask them on &lt;a href=&quot;https://talk.jekyllrb.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Talk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">You’ll find this post in your _posts directory. Go ahead and edit it and re-build the site to see your changes. You can rebuild the site in many different ways, but the most common way is to run jekyll serve, which launches a web server and auto-regenerates your site when a file is updated. Something.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/6.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Red Riding Hood</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/red-riding/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Red Riding Hood" /><published>2020-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/red-riding</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/red-riding/">&lt;p&gt;The first mass-produced book to deviate from a rectilinear format, at least in the United States, is thought to be this 1863 edition of Red Riding Hood, cut into the shape of the protagonist herself with the troublesome wolf curled at her feet. Produced by the Boston-based publisher Louis Prang, this is the first in their “Doll Series”, a set of five “die-cut” books, known also as shape books — the other titles being Robinson Crusoe, Goody Two-Shoes (also written by Red Riding Hood author Lydia Very), Cinderella, and King Winter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An 1868 Prang catalogue would later claim that such “books in the shape of a regular paper Doll… originated with us”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It would seem the claim could also extend to die cut books in general, as we can’t find anything sooner, but do let us know in the comments if you have further light to shed on this! Such books are, of course, still popular in children’s publishing today, though the die cutting is not now limited to mere outlines, as evidenced in a beautiful 2014 version of the same Little Red Riding Hood story.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The die cut has also been employed in the non-juvenile sphere as well, a recent example being Jonathan Safran Foer’s ambitious Tree of Codes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for this particular rendition of Charles Perrault’s classic tale, the text and design is by Lydia Very (1823-1901), sister of Transcendentalist poet Jones Very. The gruesome ending of the original — which sees Little Red Riding Hood being gobbled up as well as her grandmother — is avoided here, the gore giving way to the less bloody aims of the morality tale, and the lesson that one should not disobey one’s mother.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>sal</name></author><summary type="html">The first mass-produced book to deviate from a rectilinear format, at least in the United States, is thought to be this 1863 edition of Red Riding Hood, cut into the shape of the protagonist herself with the troublesome wolf curled at her feet. Produced by the Boston-based publisher Louis Prang, this is the first in their “Doll Series”, a set of five “die-cut” books, known also as shape books — the other titles being Robinson Crusoe, Goody Two-Shoes (also written by Red Riding Hood author Lydia Very), Cinderella, and King Winter.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/3.jpg" /></entry><entry><title type="html">We all wait for summer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/we-all-wait-for-summer/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="We all wait for summer" /><published>2020-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2020-01-01T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/we-all-wait-for-summer</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/we-all-wait-for-summer/">&lt;p&gt;This is changed. As I engage in the so-called “bull sessions” around and about the school, I too often find that most college men have a misconception of the purpose of education. Most of the “brethren” think that &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;education should equip&lt;/a&gt; them with the proper instruments of exploitation so that they can forever trample over the masses. Still others think that education should furnish them with noble ends rather than means to an end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It seems to me that education has a two-fold function to perform in the life of man and in society: the one is utility and the other is culture. Education must enable a man to become more efficient, to achieve with increasing facility the ligitimate goals of his life.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>jane</name></author><category term="featured" /><summary type="html">This is changed. As I engage in the so-called “bull sessions” around and about the school, I too often find that most college men have a misconception of the purpose of education. Most of the “brethren” think that education should equip them with the proper instruments of exploitation so that they can forever trample over the masses. Still others think that education should furnish them with noble ends rather than means to an end.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/assets/images/1.jpg" /></entry></feed>